<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
<!ENTITY appversion "2.1.6"> 
<!ENTITY manversion "2.1.0">
<!ENTITY date "May 2002">
<!ENTITY app "Bug Buddy">
]>

<article id="index" lang="en">
  <articleinfo>
	<title>&app; Manual V&manversion;</title>
	
	<copyright>
	  <year>2001</year>
	  <holder>Telsa Gwynne</holder>
	</copyright>

	<copyright>
	  <year>2002</year>
	  <holder>Kevin Conder</holder>
	</copyright>

	<copyright>
	  <year>2002</year>
	  <holder>Eric Baudais</holder>
	</copyright>

 <!-- translators: uncomment this:
   <copyright>
    <year>2001</year>
    <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
   </copyright>
    -->

	<publisher>
	  <publishername>GNOME Documentation Project</publishername>
	</publisher>

	&legal;

	<authorgroup>
	  <author>
		<firstname>Telsa</firstname>
		<surname>Gwynne</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>telsa@linuxchix.org</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </author>
	  
	  <editor>
		<firstname>Kevin</firstname>
		<surname>Conder</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>kevin@kevindumpscore.com</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </editor>
	  
	  <author>
		<firstname>Eric</firstname>
		<surname>Baudais</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>baudais@kkpsi.org</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </author>
	</authorgroup>

	<revhistory>
	  <revision>
		<revnumber>&app; Manual V&manversion;</revnumber>
		<date>&date;</date>
		<revdescription>
		  <para role="author">Eric Baudais
			<email>baudais@kkpsi.org</email>
		  </para>
		  <para role="publisher">GNOME Documentation Project</para>
		</revdescription>
	  </revision>

	  <revision>
		<revnumber>&app; Manual</revnumber>
		<date></date>
		<revdescription>
		  <para role="author">Telsa Gywnne
			<email>telsa@linuxchix.org</email>
		  </para>
		  <para role="publisher">GNOME Documentation Project</para>
		</revdescription>
	  </revision>
	</revhistory>

	<releaseinfo> 
	  This manual describes version &appversion; of &app;.
	</releaseinfo> 
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="intro">
	<title>Introduction</title> 

	<para>
	  <application>&app;</application> is a tool which
	  will guide you through making a bug report as painlessly as possible.
	  You can alter things at any stage, and then either send, save, or
	  abandon the resulting report. This document describes
	  version &appversion; of <application>&app;</application>: note that
	  it has changed substantially in appearance from earlier versions.
	</para>
	
	<note>
	  <title>Big Bug Buddy Changes</title>
	  <para>
		<application>Bug Buddy</application> has undergone major changes 
		recently. 
	  </para>
	  <para>
		The Gnome bug tracking system is moving from the email-based 
		debbugs installation which it originally used to the web-based
		<ulink url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/" type="http">bugzilla 
		  installation</ulink>. This is to help deal with bugs more efficiently.
		This means <application>Bug Buddy</application> has been substantially 
		rewritten to deal with the bugzilla system. It looks very similar in 
		appearance and structure, but be aware that it now talks to bugzillas. 
		Reports will only go to the old debbugs system for GNOME if bugzilla 
		doesn't have a category for the bug. 
	  </para>
	  <para>
		This also means that <application>Bug Buddy</application> has currently
		lost the ability to send bugs to the KDE and Debian bug trackers
		directly. Note that you can still save reports for those into a file 
		and then mail the file to those trackers yourself.
	  </para>
	</note>
	
	<para>
	  <application>&app;</application> can be started in a variety
	  of ways:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
		<para>
		  Open the <guimenu>main GNOME menu</guimenu> and select
		  <menuchoice>
			<guimenu>Applications</guimenu>
			<guisubmenu>Programming</guisubmenu>
			<guimenuitem>Bug Report Tool</guimenuitem>
		  </menuchoice>
		  .
		</para>
	  </listitem>
	  
	  <listitem>
		<para>
		  Run <command>bug-buddy</command> at the prompt in a terminal such
		  as <application>gnome-terminal</application> or
		  <application>xterm</application>.
		</para>
	  </listitem>
	  
	  <listitem>
		<para>
		  If you are using <application>Nautilus</application> you can 
		  double-click your mouse on a core file to start it.
		</para>
	  </listitem>
	  
	  <listitem>
		<para>
		  When a GNOME program experiences a bad crash, a <guilabel>crash
			dialog box</guilabel> is displayed. If 
		  <application>&app;</application>
		  is present on the system, then one of the options in the dialog
		  box will be to make a bug-report. Selecting that will lead you
		  to a further dialog box giving you details of the program which
		  crashed. Continuing at this stage will invoke <application>Bug Buddy
		  </application>.
		</para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>

	<para>
	  <application>&app;</application> is a very structured program.
	  At any stage you can continue forward or head backwards to correct
	  earlier details, or you can click the <guibutton>Help button</guibutton>
	  to bring up this document. 
	</para>

	<para>
	  The aim of all this is to be able to collect all the information
	  which a developer will need to reproduce the same problem and be
	  able to fix it. Some of the information generated may look a bit
	  off-putting, but don't delete it. It will be useful.
	</para>
  </sect1>

  
  <sect1 id="welcome">
	<title>Welcome to Bug Buddy</title>
	<para>
	  &app; opens with a welcome and some important buttons at the bottom of 
	  the screen.  The four buttons at the very bottom of the screen will 
	  not change in &app; while using the program.
<!--
	  <figure id="bug-buddy">
		<title>&app; Startup Window</title>
		<screenshot>
		  <mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
			  <imagedata fileref="figures/bug-buddy-welcome.png" format="PNG"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
			  <phrase>Shows &app;'s main window.  Contains the Debugging 
				Options, About, Cancel, Back, and Forward buttons.</phrase>
			</textobject>
		  </mediaobject>
		</screenshot>
	  </figure>
-->
	  <itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guibutton>About</guibutton> button gives information about 
			<application>&app;'s</application> version and copyright holders. 
			There is a <guibutton>Credits</guibutton> button in the 
			<guilabel>About Bug Buddy</guilabel> dialog which lists the 
			authors of the program and documentation.
<!--
			<figure id="about-bug-buddy">
			  <title>About Bug Buddy dialog</title>
			  <screenshot>
				<mediaobject>
				  <imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="figures/about.png" format="PNG"/>
				  </imageobject>
				  <textobject>
					<phrase>Shows the About Bug Buddy dialog with the Credits 
					  and OK buttons.</phrase>
				  </textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			  </screenshot>
			</figure>
-->
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> button is used to exit 
			<application>&app;</application> and cancel the bug report.  The 
			<guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> button brings up the 
			<guilabel>Question</guilabel> dialog which asks if you really want 
			to exit the program.  Pressing the <guibutton>No</guibutton> button 
			will close the dialog and bring you back to the program so you can 
			continue your bug report.  Pressing the <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> 
			button will close the program and cancel the bug report you were 
			making.
<!--
			<figure id="question-dialog">
			  <title>Question Dialog</title>
			  <screenshot>
				<mediaobject>
				  <imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="figures/question.png" format="PNG"/>
				  </imageobject>
				  <textobject>
					<phrase>Shows the Question dialog.  Contains the No and 
					  Yes buttons.</phrase>
				  </textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			  </screenshot>
			</figure>
-->
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guibutton>Back</guibutton> button will bring up the previous 
			screen so you can change your report.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button will bring up the next 
			screen to continue your bug report.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</para>

	<para>
	  In <application>&app;'s</application> startup window the 
	  <guibutton>Show Debugging Options</guibutton> button shows the debugging 
	  options available.  This allows you to perform back traces on a crashed 
	  application or to include the core file created when the application 
	  crashed.  
	  <application>&app;</application> will add the back trace or core file to 
	  the bug report automatically.  If you do not want to include the back 
	  trace or core file you can delete them in the 
	  <xref linkend="confirmation"/>.  You can also copy the output of 
	  <application>&app;'s</application> debugging window to the clipboard or 
	  save it as a file.
	</para>

	<para>
	  <application>&app;</application> has three options when writing a bug 
	  report.  When you are done with the debugging information click on the 
	  <guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button to proceed to the next step in 
	  submitting your bug.
	
	  <variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
		  <term>Debug nothing</term>
		  <listitem>
			<para>
			  This is the default option. If you did not start
			  <application>Bug Buddy</application> following a crash, and
			  do not have a core file you want debugged, pick this.
<!--
			  <figure id="debug-nothing">
				<title>Debug Nothing Window</title>
				<screenshot>
				  <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
					  <imagedata fileref="figures/debug-nothing.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
					  <phrase>
						Shows the pull down menu and the Hide Debugging 
						Options button with the rest greyed out.</phrase>
					</textobject>
				  </mediaobject>
				</screenshot>
			  </figure>
-->
			</para>
		  </listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
		  <term>Debug core file</term>
		  <listitem>
			<para>
			  If <application>&app;</application> began because you 
			  double-clicked on a file named <filename>core</filename> in the
			  file manager, select this. Also select this if you have a core file
			  which you know was created as a result of the bug you are reporting.
			  An extra box will appear where you can tell it where the core file
			  lives.
<!--
			  <figure id="debug-core-file">
				<title>Debug Core File Window</title>
				<screenshot>
				  <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
					  <imagedata fileref="figures/debug-core-file.png" format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
					  <phrase>
						Shows the startup window with the core file debugging 
						options.  These include the pull down menu, Start 
						button, Core File text box to enter the core file, 
						Browse button, the main text box, Copy button, Save 
						button, and Hide Debugging Options.</phrase>
					</textobject>
				  </mediaobject>
				</screenshot>
			  </figure>
-->
			</para>
		  </listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		
		<varlistentry>
		  <term>Debug crashed application</term>
		  <listitem>
			<para>
			  If <application>Bug Buddy</application> began because you said
			  yes to <quote>Report a bug</quote> in a dialog box telling you 
			  something had crashed, select this. If you do so, you will be 
			  prompted for two things. These should be filled in already for 
			  you. If they are not, take a moment to fill in:
			</para>
			
			<itemizedlist>
			  <listitem>
				<para>
				  <guilabel>Binary</guilabel>: In this box you must type the
				  name of the program as you would type it at the command-line.
				  For example, if <application>Nautilus</application>
				  crashed, you would need to type <command>nautilus</command> here.
				</para>
			  </listitem>
			  <listitem>
				<para>
				  <guilabel>Process ID</guilabel>: In this box you must type
				  the process ID or <acronym>PID</acronym>. This will probably
				  be available from the original dialog box where you selected
				  <quote>Report a bug</quote>. If you have closed that window, 
				  you can find it by starting the 
				  <application>Procman System Monitor</application> through 
				  selecting
				  <menuchoice>
					<guimenu>Applications</guimenu>
					<guisubmenu>System Tools</guisubmenu>
					<guimenuitem>Procman System Monitor</guimenuitem>
				  </menuchoice>
				  or typing <command>procman</command> at the command line. You
				  will find the PID in the right-hand column and the command
				  in the left-hand column.
				</para>
			  </listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		  </listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	  </variablelist>
	</para>
  </sect1>
  
  
  <sect1 id="product">
	<title>Select a Product</title>
	<para>
	  This page gives you a list of products, from which you can select.  
	  Select the product you want to report a bug in and click on the 
	  <guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button to proceed to the next screen.
<!--
	  <figure id="select-product">
		<title>Select a Product Window</title>
		<screenshot>
		  <mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
			  <imagedata fileref="figures/select-product.png" format="PNG"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
			  <phrase>Shows the Select a Product main window with a list of 
				the products to select from.</phrase>
			</textobject>
		  </mediaobject>
		</screenshot>
	  </figure>
-->
	</para>

	<para>
	  If you wish to submit a bug, but the product isn't listed then click 
	  on <guilabel>The product is not listed above</guilabel> checkbox.  
	  You will skip the <link linkend="component">Component</link> section 
	  and proceed directly to the <xref linkend="description"/>.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="updating">
	  <title>Updating Product Listing</title>
	  <para>
		If this is the first time you have run Bug Buddy, you will see
		this page. It also appears if it has been two weeks since
		the last update. Otherwise it will not appear. 
	  </para>
	  <para>
		A dialog box telling you <application>Bug Buddy</application> wants   
		to update its list of information will appear and gives you the option
		to stop or configure the proxy settings. It will save this information 
		by default into your 
		<filename class="directory">.gnome2/bug-buddy.d/</filename> directory.
		To get this information, it needs to talk to bugzilla, so your net
		connection will have to be up.
	  </para>
	</sect2>
  
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="component">
	<title>Select a Component</title>
	<para>
	  There are three sections to fill in:
	</para>
	
	<variablelist>
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Component</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The product selected will have one or more components to it.
			If there is only one component (typically a general component),
			click on it. If there are several components, select the most
			likely looking one.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Version</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			This is the version number for the program or package you're
			reporting a bug in. It may already be filled in. If not, find
			out the version through the package's <guilabel>About</guilabel> ]
			box and fill it in here.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Severity</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			This is the severity of the bug, as you feel it. There are several
			choices in decreasing order:
		  </para>
		  <orderedlist>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				An enhancement bug is a request for enhancement rather than
				a bug describing a problem. "It would be nice if.."
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A trivial bug is precisely that: trivial. It is typically a
				cosmetic problem such as misspelled words or misaligned text.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A minor bug involves either a minor loss of function, or a
				larger problem but one which has an easy workaround.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A normal bug is the typical sort of bug. This is the default
				and probably won't need increasing.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A major bug involves a major loss of function.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A critical bug is one which involves a crash, a severe memory
				leak, or loss of data.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				A blocker bug is rare and usually assigned as a blocker by a
				developer. It is a bug which stops other things being fixed
				and which must be fixed before other bugs can be closed.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
		  </orderedlist>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
	
	<para>
	  When all three sections are filled in, the <guibutton>Forward</guibutton>
	  button will become enabled, and you can continue. 
	</para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="frequent-bugs">
	<title>Frequently Reported Bugs</title>

	<para>
	  There isn't any information to fill in, but take a moment to look 
	  at the bugs displayed here.  These bugs are the most common bugs 
	  reported in all of GNOME.  Look at the product and description to 
	  determine if the bug you were going to report is similar to any of the 
	  bugs displayed here.
	</para>


	<para>
	  If you bug matches one of the bugs or is reasonably close you can click 
	  on it to bring up bugzilla in your browser.  Then you should 
	  add a comment to the existing bug instead of filing a new bug.  If 
	  none of the bugs displayed here look like the bug you are going to 
	  report then click on the <guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button to 
	  continue to the next section.
	</para>

  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="description">
	<title>Bug Description</title>

	<para>
	  There are four sections which need to be filled in:
	</para>
	
	<variablelist>
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Summary for the bug report</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> section
			will be used as the <quote>Subject</quote> header of the emailed 
			bug report, which will turn into a <quote>Summary</quote> line in 
			Bugzilla. Good subject lines are specific and do not just say 
			<quote>Bug</quote> or <quote>It crashed</quote>. 
			<quote>Crash when I try to save</quote> or 
			<quote>Forgets my preferences</quote> are much better. Hackers 
			will read these summaries when looking for something they can fix 
			and clear one-sentence summaries will catch their attention. You 
			must fill this in. If you do not, <application>&app;</application>
			will tell you to.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Full description of the bug</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			The <guilabel>Description</guilabel> section is where
			you describe what happened, what you did, and what you expected to
			happen. You should write good concise sentences describing the bug 
			as best as you can.  The section is divided into three parts:
		  </para>

		  <variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
			  <term>Description of Problem:</term>
			  <listitem>
				<para>
				  The <guilabel>Description of Problem</guilabel> section 
				  is where you describe what happened.  The bug produced some 
				  unexpected behavior and you should describe exactly 
				  the unexpected behavior.  This includes any error messages 
				  or warnings.
				</para>
			  </listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
			  <term>Steps to reproduce the problem:</term>
			  <listitem>
				<para>
				  The <guilabel>Steps to reproduce the problem</guilabel> 
				  section is where you describe what you did to make the 
				  bug appear.  You should use short sentences telling exactly 
				  what you did to produce the bug.  Be as particular as 
				  possible in this section to describe exactly each step you 
				  took to produce the bug.  Developers will use your 
				  instructions to try and reproduce the bug on their systems.
				</para>
			  </listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
			  <term>Actual Results</term>
			  <listitem>
				<para>
				  The <guilabel>Actual Results</guilabel> section is where you 
				  describe what you expected to happen.  The bug stopped you 
				  from doing something and you should describe what you 
				  wanted to happen here.  It can as simple as, (<quote>I 
				  expected the application to load a PNG file</quote>).
				</para>
			  </listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		  </variablelist>

		  <para>
			Other good things to include:
		  </para>
		  
		  <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Exact copies of any error messages;
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Your window manager name and version (especially if the bug involves 
				moving things around the screen or mouse focus problems);
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Any special versions of binary RPM, debs, or GNOME specific 
				versions such as Ximian GNOME or Garnome.  Include the name and 
				the version you installed;
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				If you can make it happen in one way, and not in another way,
				include that. If there are two ways to do something (a menu
				selection and a typed command, for example), and only one triggers
				the bug, definitely include that;
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Why you think it is a bug. What should have happened instead?
				Whilst this is obvious for some things, (<quote>It shouldn't 
				  crash when I try to save the file</quote>) it is not obvious 
				for others. Give a better way for the program to behave. 
				(<quote>If it can't save the file, it should tell me so that I 
				  don't keep editing it without realizing I am wasting my 
				  effort</quote>.);
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Sometimes screen-shots can help demonstrate bugs. Please do not send one
				in a Bug Buddy report! But if you have one, mention that you have it,
				so that a bug-fixer who would like to see it can email you about it;
			  </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			  <para>
				Sometimes a file won't load correctly or at all.  You should 
				always include the file with these type of bugs.
			  </para>
			</listitem>
		  </itemizedlist>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
	
	<para>
	  If you have any suggestions on what caused it or how to fix it,
	  wonderful. If not, don't worry. Just explain what happened. If
	  a developer needs more information, they can mail you back for
	  it. 
	</para>
<!--	
	<para>
	  If you have a (short!) text file which contains information of use
	  you can include it here, too. If you have a small HTML file which
	  crashes your editor, or two sets of options for a program where one
	  works and the other doesn't, these are the sort of things to include
	  here. Just put the name of the file into the <guilabel>Include a 
		text file</guilabel> box at the bottom. 
	</para>
-->
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="mail-config">
	<title>Mail Configuration</title>

	<para>
	  <application>&app;</application> gives you two options.  You can 
	  <guilabel>Use sendmail directly</guilabel> or <guilabel>Just save to a 
		file so I can submit a bug report manually</guilabel>.  If you want 
	  to send the bug report to bugzilla then select the option 
	  <guilabel>Use sendmail directly</guilabel>.  If you want to save the 
	  bug report to a file and submit it by yourself you should select the 
	  second option.
	</para>
	
	<para>
	  If you want to send a bug report to bugzilla directly then you need to 
	  fill out these pieces of information.  It makes very good guesses so you 
	  should be able to skip straight ahead. 
	</para>

	<variablelist>
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Your name</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			Bug Buddy works this out itself, but if you want to change it you
			can do this here.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Email address</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			Please enter a valid email address for you here.  This is so developers
			can request more information from you, or inform you of a fix for your bug.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Full path of sendmail</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			This allows you to check that Bug Buddy is looking in the right
			place when it tries to send email. You will almost certainly not
			need to change this. 
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  
	</variablelist>
	
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="confirmation">
	<title>Confirmation</title>
	<para>
	  Once you have finished your report, you can review the report and
	  decide what to do with it. You will probably want to submit it to 
	  the bug tracking system, but if you want to send it elsewhere for
	  some reason you can. You can choose from:
	</para>
	<variablelist>
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Send report</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			If you selected to <guilabel>Use sendmail directly</guilabel> in 
			the previous section you will see the 
			<guibutton>Send report</guibutton> button where the 
			<guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button usually is located.  
			Clicking on <guibutton>Send report</guibutton>
			will bring up a <guilabel>Question</guilabel> dialog.  Clicking on 
			<guibutton>Submit</guibutton> will email the bug report to the 
			bug tracker.  Clicking on <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> will take 
			you back to the <guilabel>Confirmation</guilabel> section.
		  </para>
		  <note>
			<title>bugs.gnome.org and bugzilla.gnome.org</title>
			<para>
			  Even though the report should end up at bugzilla, you will see
			  that the address is for bugs.gnome.org. This is fine. Don't change
			  it. It's the staging-post which forwards reports on to bugzilla. 
			  If bugzilla has no category for it, then bugs.gnome.org will keep
			  it. 
			</para>
		  </note>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	  <varlistentry>
		<term>Save</term>
		<listitem>
		  <para>
			If you selected to <guilabel>Just save to a file so I can submit 
			  the bug report manually</guilabel> in the previous section you 
			will see a <guilabel>Save in</guilabel> text box.  Fill in the 
			file where you want the bug report saved to or just click on 
			<guibutton>Browse</guibutton>.  If the file already
			exists, it will ask you whether to overwrite the file or not.  
			Clicking on <guibutton>Save</guibutton> will save the bug report 
			to the file.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
  </sect1>
  
  
  <sect1 id="summary">
	<title>Summary</title>
	<para>
	  <application>Bug Buddy</application> will tell you what it has
	  done with your bug report. That's it.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Thank you for reporting your bug.
	</para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="bugs">
	<title>Known bugs and limitations</title>
	
	<para>
	  <application>Bug Buddy</application> has very few bugs or limitations.
	  Currently known:
	</para>
	
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
		<para>
		  There is an applet called <application>Tick-A-Stat</application>
		  which can be set to look for core files and timestamp them with
		  their origin and date. <application>Bug Buddy</application> cannot
		  read files which <application>Tick-A-Stat</application> has done
		  this to. 
		</para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
  </sect1>
</article>
