<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- -*- indent-tabs-mode: nil -*- -->
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
<!ENTITY appversion "2.8"> 
<!ENTITY manversion "2.8">
<!ENTITY date "September 2002">
<!ENTITY app "Bug Buddy">
<!ENTITY application "<application>Bug Buddy</application>">
]>

<article id="index" lang="en">
  <articleinfo>
	<title>&app; Manual</title>
	
	<copyright>
	  <year>2001</year>
	  <holder>Telsa Gwynne</holder>
	</copyright>

	<copyright>
	  <year>2002</year>
	  <holder>Kevin Conder</holder>
	</copyright>

	<copyright>
	  <year>2002</year>
	  <holder>Eric Baudais</holder>
	</copyright>

	<copyright>
	  <year>2004</year>
	  <holder>Shaun McCance</holder>
	</copyright>

 <!-- translators: uncomment this:
   <copyright>
    <year>2001</year>
    <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin translation)</holder>
   </copyright>
    -->

	<publisher>
	  <publishername>GNOME Documentation Project</publishername>
	</publisher>

	&legal;

	<authorgroup>
	  <author>
		<firstname>Telsa</firstname>
		<surname>Gwynne</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>telsa@linuxchix.org</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </author>
	  
	  <editor>
		<firstname>Kevin</firstname>
		<surname>Conder</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>kevin@kevindumpscore.com</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </editor>
	  
	  <author>
		<firstname>Eric</firstname>
		<surname>Baudais</surname>
		<affiliation>
		  <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
		  <address>
			<email>baudais@kkpsi.org</email>
		  </address>
		</affiliation>
	  </author>

	  <author>
	    <firstname>Shaun</firstname>
	    <surname>McCance</surname>
	    <affiliation>
	      <orgname>GNOME Documentation Project</orgname>
	    </affiliation>
	    <email>shaunm@gnome.org</email>
	  </author>
	</authorgroup>

	<revhistory>
	  <revision>
	    <revnumber>Version &manversion;</revnumber>
	    <date>&date;</date>
	    <revdescription>
	      <para role="author">Shaun McCance</para>
	      <para role="publisher">GNOME Documentation Project</para>
	    </revdescription>
	  </revision>
	  <revision>
		<revnumber>&app; Manual V2.1.0</revnumber>
		<date>May 2002</date>
		<revdescription>
		  <para role="author">Eric Baudais
			<email>baudais@kkpsi.org</email>
		  </para>
		  <para role="publisher">GNOME Documentation Project</para>
		</revdescription>
	  </revision>

	  <revision>
		<revnumber>&app; Manual</revnumber>
		<date></date>
		<revdescription>
		  <para role="author">Telsa Gywnne
			<email>telsa@linuxchix.org</email>
		  </para>
		  <para role="publisher">GNOME Documentation Project</para>
		</revdescription>
	  </revision>
	</revhistory>

	<releaseinfo> 
	  This manual describes version &appversion; of &app;.
	</releaseinfo> 
  </articleinfo>

<sect1 id="intro">
  <title>Introduction</title> 

  <para>&application; is a tool which will guide you through making a bug
  report as painlessly as possible.  You can alter things at any stage,
  and then either send, save, or abandon the resulting report. This
  document describes version &appversion; of &application;.</para>
  <para>&application; can be started a number of ways:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Choose <menuchoice><guimenu>Programming</guimenu>
      <guimenuitem>Bug Report Tool</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
      from the <guimenu>Applications</guimenu> menu.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Run <command>bug-buddy</command> at the prompt in a terminal
      such as <application>gnome-terminal</application> or from the
      <application>Run Application</application> dialog.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>If you are using the <application>Nautilus</application>
      file manager, you can double-click on a core file to start
      &application;.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>When a GNOME program experiences a bad crash, a crash dialog
      box is displayed. If &application; is present on
      the system, then one of the options will be <guibutton>Inform
      Developers</guibutton>.  This button will launch
      &application;.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>&application; is a structured program.  At any stage you can continue
  forward or head backwards to correct earlier details.  The aim of all this
  is to be able to collect all the information which a developer will need to
  reproduce the same problem fix it.  Some of the information generated by
  &application; may be unfamiliar to you, but don't delete it.  It will be
  useful to the developers.</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="welcome">
  <title>Welcome to Bug Buddy</title>

  <para>&application; opens with a welcome and some
  important buttons at the bottom of the screen.  The four buttons at
  the very bottom of the screen will not change in
  &application; while using the program.</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The <guibutton>About</guibutton> button gives information about
      <application>&app;'s</application> version and copyright holders.
      There is a <guibutton>Credits</guibutton> button in the
      <application>About Bug Buddy</application> dialog which lists the 
      authors of the program and documentation.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> button is used to exit
      &application; and cancel the bug report.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The <guibutton>Back</guibutton> button will bring up the previous
      screen so you can change information earlier in the report.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The <guibutton>Forward</guibutton> button will bring up the next 
      screen to continue your bug report.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>When you start &application;, you will be asked to select what kind
  of report to file.  The following options are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>The application does not function
      correctly</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this option if the application produced incorrect
      results or otherwise behaved differently than you expected.
      </para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>The documentation is wrong</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this option if the documentation does not
      describe the actual behavior of the application, or if the documentation
      is incomplete</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>The translation is wrong</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this option if you are using the application
      in a language other than the application's native language, and the
      translations in the application are incorrect.  Also select this
      option if translated documentation is incorrect.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Request a missing feature</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this option to request that a feature be
      added to the application.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Debug a crashed or running application</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this option to report an application crash.  Note
      that if you start &application; from a crash dialog box, then this will
      be selected automatically, and you will not see the first screen of
      options.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="reporting-crash">
  <title>Reporting a Crash</title>

  <para>If you are reporting a crash, &application; will show the available
  debugging options.  This allows you to perform back traces on a crashed
  application or to include the core file created when the application
  crashed.  &application; will add the back trace or core file to the bug
  report automatically.</para>

  <para>If &application; was started from a crash dialog box, then the
  back trace for the application will automatically be included.  The
  debugging information is hidden when &application; is started from a
  crash dialog box.  You can click on the <guibutton>Show Debugging
  Options</guibutton> button to show the them.</para>
  <para>&application; has three options when reporting a crash:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Debug nothing</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>This is the default option. If you did not start
      &application; following a crash and do not have a core file to debug,
      select this option.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Debug core file</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if you have a core file which you know was
      created as a result of the bug you are reporting.  After selecting this
      option, you can click on the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button to
      locate the core file on your system.  If you started &application;
      by double-clicking on a core file in the file manager, this option
      will be automatically selected.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Debug crashed application</guilabel></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If &application; was started from a crash dialog box, this
        option will be automatically selected.  If this option is selected,
        &application; will prompt you for a binary file and a process ID.
        If &application; was started from a crash dialog box, these two
        fields should be filled out automatically.  Otherwise, you will
        need to enter the information manually.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Binary file</guilabel></term>
            <listitem><para>This is the name of the application as you would
            type it at a command prompt.  For example, if you are reporting
            a crash in the <application>Nautilus</application> file manager,
            you would enter <command>nautilus</command>.</para></listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Process ID</guilabel></term>
            <listitem><para>This is the process ID, or <acronym>PID</acronym>,
            of the running application.  The
            <application>System Monitor</application> displays the process ID
            of every running application.  You can start the <application>System
            Monitor</application> by selecting <menuchoice><guimenu>System
            Tools</guimenu><guimenuitem>System Monitor</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
            from the <guimenu>Applications</guimenu> menu.</para></listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>This screen contains a text area where debugging options are displayed.
  You can click on the <guibutton>Copy</guibutton> button to copy the contents
  of the text area to the clipboard.  You can also click on the
  <guibutton>Save</guibutton> to save the contents of the text area
  to a file.</para>
</sect1>
  
<sect1 id="product">
  <title>Selecting a Product</title>

  <para>The product selection page provides a list of products from which you
  can select.  You can choose to view the listing by product or by application.
  To view by the products as stored in the bugs database, select the
  <guibutton>Show Products</guibutton> radio button.  To view by applications
  as they appear on your system, select the <guibutton>Show
  Applications</guibutton> radio button.<!-- Note to translators:  The product
  names and descriptions come from bugzilla, and are not translated.  You may
  want to mention this in the translated documentation. --></para>

  <sect2 id="updating">
    <title>Updating the Product Listing</title>

    <para>&application; maintains a local list of products for bug reports.
    Each time &application; starts, it checks this list of products against
    checksums on the bug database servers.  If the checksums do not match,
    &application; will offer to update the product listing.</para>
    <para>To get the most recent list of products, you should select
    <guibutton>Update</guibutton>.  However, you may choose not to update
    the product listing at this time.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="component">
  <title>Selecting a Component</title>

  <para>After selecting the product, you can select the component, version,
  and severity of the problem you are reporting.</para>

  <para>Each product will have one or more components associated with it.
  For instance, the <application>Epiphany</application> web browser has the
  <literal>Printing</literal> component for problems related to printing web
  pages, the <literal>Bookmarks</literal> component for problems related to
  the bookmarks system, and a number of other components for other types of
  problems.  Some simple applications will only have one component, typically
  named <literal>general</literal>.  Most products will contain a component
  for documentation problems, typically named <literal>docs</literal>.  If
  you are not sure which component to select for your report, select the
  <literal>general</literal> component if it exists.<!-- Note to translators:
  the componets and their descriptions are not translated.  when translating
  this paragraph, you should maintain the strings inside the literal tags.
  --></para>

  <para>The <guilabel>Version</guilabel> drop-down box allows you to select
  which version of the application is causing the problem.  You can find the
  version of most applications by selecting <menuchoice><guimenu>Help</guimenu>
  <guimenuitem>About</guimenuitem></menuchoice> in the application's main
  window.  If you are unsure which version you are using, set the version
  to <literal>unspecified</literal>.</para>

  <para>You can set what you feel is the severity of the problem you are
  reporting.  The <guilabel>Severity</guilabel> drop-down box has the
  following choices:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>blocker</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if the problem blocks development or
      testing work on the application.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>critical</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if the application crashed, or if the
      problem causes a loss of data.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>major</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select his if the problem is a major loss of
      functionality; for instance, if a menu item is broken, data
      output is extremely incorrect, or the application is otherwise
      difficult or impossible to use.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>normal</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if a minor part of the application is
      nonfunctional or broken.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>minor</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if there is a minor loss of functionality,
      or if an easy workaround for the problem is available.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>trivial</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if the problem is cosmetic; for instance,
      if a word is misspelled or text is misaligned.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>enhancement</guilabel><!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Select this if the report is a request for a new feature
      or new functionality.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="frequent-bugs">
  <title>Frequently Reported Bugs</title>

  <para>Before submitting your report, &application; will display a list of the
  most common bugs reported to the GNOME bug tracking system.  Since GNOME is
  being tested by people all over the world, somebody may have already reported
  the problem you've found.  Please take a moment to review the most frequently
  reported bugs to see if your problem is already reported.  If you find your
  problem on this list, there is no need to report it again.</para>

  <para>If your problem is listed, you can click on the bug number to show
  the full report in your web browser.  If you have additional information
  to add to the report, please use the web page to do so.</para>
</sect1>
  
<sect1 id="description">
  <title>Bug Description</title>
  <para>&application; will ask you to provide a summary and description of
  the bug you are filing.  If at all possible, please make the report in
  English.  Most developers speak English, although not necessarily as
  their native language.  Filing your report in English will ensure that
  all developers can understand the problem, which makes it more likely
  that the problem will be fixed.</para>

  <para>The <guilabel>Description</guilabel> text area allows you to
  describe the problem fully.  &application; automatically inserts a
  template into the description with the following headers:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description of Problem<!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Include a short paragraph providing a brief
      description of the problem you are reporting.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Steps to reproduce the problem<!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Include an itemized list of the steps to take to
      reproduce the problem.  Developers cannot fix a problem if they
      do not know how to reproduce it.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Actual results<!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Include a short description of what the application
      actually does when you execute the above steps.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expected results<!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>Include a short description of what you expect the
      application to do when you execute the above steps.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Additional information<!-- DO NOT TRANSLATE --></term>
      <listitem><para>If you have any additional information about the
      problem, please include that information here.  For instance, if
      the programs gives any error messages, you should include that
      information.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>You do not have to fill in all the fields, or follow the template
  exactly.  However, the above information is what is generally useful to
  developers in most bug reports.</para>

  <para>If you have any suggestions on what caused the problem or how to
  fix it, you can include that.  If not, don't worry.  Just explain what
  happened.  If a developer needs more information, they may email you
  back asking for it.</para>
</sect1>
  
<sect1 id="mail-config">
  <title>Mail Configuration</title>

  <para>&application; gives you two options.  You can either send the report
  directly to the bugs database using <application>sendmail</application>,
  or you can save the report to a file and submit it manually.</para>

  <para>If you want to send a bug report to bugzilla directly then you need to
  fill out the <guilabel>Sendmail Settings</guilabel>.  &application; will try
  to guess the values for these settings.  If the information is incorrect,
  fill in the correct settings.</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Name</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>&application; will set this to your name as it is set
      on your system.  If you want to use a different value, you can change
      this setting.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Email</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>Please enter a valid email address where you can be
      reached.  Developers may wish to request more information to help them
      solve the problem you report.  You will also be notified when the bug
      has been closed.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guilabel>Path of sendmail</guilabel></term>
      <listitem><para>&application; uses <application>sendmail</application>
      to send email to the bug tracking system to submit the report.  This
      field specifies the exact location of the <command>sendmail</command>
      command on your system.  You will almost certainly not need to change
      this.</para></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="confirmation">
  <title>Confirmation</title>

  <para>Once you have finished your report, you can review the report and decide
  what to do with it.  You will probably want to submit it to the bug tracking
  system, but you can send it elsewhere if you need to do so.</para>

  <para>Your options on this screen will depend on what you chose on the previous
  screen.  See <xref linkend="mail-config"/> for more information.</para>

  <sect2 id="confirmation-send">
    <title>Sending the Report</title>

    <para>If you selected <guilabel>Use sendmail directly</guilabel> on the
    previous screen, you will see the <guibutton>Send report</guibutton> button.
    &application; will provide <guilabel>To</guilabel> and <guilabel>Cc</guilabel>
    fields.  You can use these fields to add recipients to the bug report email.
    As in most mail clients, the proper format is a comma-seperated list of
    email addresses.</para>

    <para>Clicking the <guibutton>Send Report</guibutton> button will send your
    report to the bug tracking system.  You will be sent an automated email from
    the bug tracking system with a link to a web page where you can track the
    status of the bug.</para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="confirmation-save">
    <title>Saving the Report</title>

    <para>If you selected <guilabel>Just save to a file so I can submit
    a bug report manually</guilabel> on the previous screen, you will
    see a <guibutton>Save</guibutton> button.  To save the report, enter
    a filename in the <guilabel>Save in</guilabel> field and click
    <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.  &application; will save the report
    to the specified file.  You can email this report to the bug
    tracking system or to a developer at a later time.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="summary">
  <title>Report Summary</title>

  <para>The final screen in &application; will provide a summary of what
  was done with the report.  You can click <guibutton>Close</guibutton>
  to close &application;.</para>

  <para>Thank you for taking the time to report your bug.  Reporting problems
  with helps the developers create better applications for you.  By reporting
  your problems and suggestions to the bug tracking system, you are playing an
  important role in the development of free software.</para>
</sect1>
</article>
